Chendi Li

lichendi.cs@gmail.com

looking for a 2022 Fall Ph.D. program

Personal website

I am currently a graduate student at the State Key Laboratory of Computer Architecture, Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences (CARCH, ICT, CAS), supervised by Prof. Yunquan Zhang. My research interests including high-performance computing, CPU and GPU acceleration, optimized BLAS library.

The expected graduation date is 2022 Summer.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science, Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences Sep 2019 — June 2022 Bachelor of Computer Science, Hunan Agricultural University Sep 2014 — June 2018

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student Research Assistant

Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Beijing

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Jan 2018 — Jun 2019

Sep 2019 — Now

Beijing

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. [IEEE ISPA 2021] Chendi Li, Haipeng Jia, Hang Cao, et al. AutoTSMM: An Auto-tuning Framework for Building High-Performance Tall-and-Skinny Matrix-Matrix Multiplication on CPUs.
- 2. [IEEE ICPADS 2021, under review] Jianyu Yao, Boqian Shi, Chunyang Xiang, Haipeng Jia, Chendi Li, et al. IAAT: An Input-Aware Adaptive Tuning framework for Small GEMM.
- 3. [CCF HPC China 2020] Chendi Li, Guangting Zhang, Haipeng Jia. Fast Computation of Elementary Functions on ARM Platforms(in Chinese)

RESEARCH PROJECTS

AutoTSMM, Author Nov 2020 - Now

 I designed AutoTSMM independently, which is used to build high-Performance tall-and-skinny matrix multiplication on all mainstream CPUs. And the performance is competitive with state-of-the-art TSMM implementation from Intel MKL and outperforms all conventional GEMM implementations on X86 and ARMv8 platforms. AutoTSMM was accepted by IEEE ISPA 2021.

OpenBLAS, Contributor Nov 2020 — Now

 OpenBLAS is an open-source BLAS library. I'm responsible for optimizing pre-pack matrix-matrix multiplication and triangular solve with multiple right-hand-sides(TRSM) on ARMv8 and X86 platforms.

IAAT, Contributor Nov 2020 - Now

• IAAT is a just-in-time(JIT) small GEMM framework targeting CPUs. I helped to launch the project and did a lot of investigations on how to use JIT tools. I participate in brainstorming and conferences every week. IAAT is being reviewed by IEEE ICPADS 2021.

OpenVML, Co-author Jan 2020 — Oct 2020

• OpenVML is a vector math library. I was responsible for optimizing the math functions on the ARMv8 platform. The OpenVML achieve a outstanding performance improvement C standard library function and ARMPL. The paper "Fast Computation of Elementary Functions on ARM Platform" was published in HPC China 2020.

AutoFFT, Contributor Jan 2018 — June 2019

AutoFFT is a template-based FFT codes auto-generation framework for ARM and X86 CPUs. I was mainly responsible for optimizing small-scale FFT on ARMv8 architecture. Later, I also did some preliminary work on multi-threading and 2D-FFT. AutoFFT is the first research project I participated in, and I learned a lot from it. AutoFFT was published in SC'19 and TPDS'20.

AWARDS & HONORS

2021 ICT first-class scholarships 2020 ICT second-class scholarship

HUNAU collegiate programming contest first prize; Outstanding volunteer 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools Linux, Git, Vim, CMake, GDB, OpenMP, Pthreads **Programming/Scripting** C, Latex, Assembly, Python, Neon intrinsic